So the intro of
a video is basically
someone doing this with
our YouTube gift. They
get our box and
they go, oh, what
is it? I hope
it's what I think
it is. And then
they look and they
go, oh, oh my
gosh, I love you
so much. Go and
get the cream, the
strawberries and the toilet
plunger. We're about to
have a good time.
Or they do this.
Oh my gosh, it's
not, is it?
Are you f***ing kidding
me? A Casio? We
are done. So in
this video, I'm going
to teach you how
to write intros that
create the first reaction
with your viewers. And
what we're going to
do is we're going
to cover what makes
a great intro, how
to match or exceed
viewer expectations, how to
structure it, and then
how to connect your
intro to your first
lesson. And then I'm
going to show you
how to use my
AI to do pretty
much all of the
work for you, making
most of this completely
redundant. But don't skip
ahead to the AI
bit because you need
to understand intros properly
first. Otherwise, you're not
going to know how
to. Edit the AI
and you'll only ever
be as good as
the AI, which ain't
going to cut it
when everyone's using it.
You won't listen to
me. I know you're
just going to skip.
I can see what
you're doing. All right.
So let's start with
what makes a great
intro and we're going
to play a game.
So I want you
to tell me what
you expect this video
here to deliver on.
So firstly, I want
you to think about
what your visual expectations
are. Like, what do
you expect the video
to look like based
on this packaging? Now,
it will probably be.
Different for all of
us. But what I
expect to see when
I see a video
shot in a gym
with a big old
arm is I'm going
to click play and
it's going to be
someone with big arms,
probably in some sort
of environment that looks
a bit fitness related.
Now, I'm not going
to be annoyed if
it's not shot in
a gym. If there's
a weedy dude there
giving me bicep advice,
I won't have my
expectations met or match
or exceeded. And I'm
probably not going to
want to listen to
this new channel I've
discovered. So I'm off.
So one of the
easiest. Ways to hook
a viewer early is
to visually meet their
expectations. The thumbnail might
have promised. So here's
some examples of this
in action. You see
this channel called A
Theory of One. They
made this thumbnail and
this was her opening
shot. It's the same
thing. And then this
is old Charlie. He
has this sinfully ugly
thumbnail and his awful
production quality.
But you know what?
The packaging sets up.
This is going to
be a low production,
no frills, high value
video. So I see
his whiteboard and I
think, you know what?
This is probably going
to deliver on my
expectations. And then this
is Matt D 'Avella.
So he's got this
beautifully cinematic thumbnail. He's
in the gym. And
then his first shot
is this, which matches
my expectations. I'm going
to get some beautiful
cinematography in a gym.
So we want to
keep in mind is
that viewers will have
expectations for your video
quality and what the
intro looks like based
on your thumbnail image.
All right. So next,
what I want to
know is what are
the top three questions
you want answered from
this video? So for
me, it's. Will I
actually gain an inch?
How do you do
it? And can I
do it? Or is
this going to be
super hard for more
advanced people? Now, the
reason I'm asking you
to do this is
because in order to
create an intro that
meets or exceeds our
viewers expectations, we need
to make sure our
intro tells the viewers
it's going to deliver
on the things they
expect. So step one
of every intro you
make is to simply
ask yourself, what are
the top three questions
my viewers are going
to want to know
the answers to based
on the packaging I've
created? And then you
just note that down.
And you also want
to make sure that
your production is visually
in line with your
thumbnail too. Now, if
you're not sure what
your viewers want, here's
a simple little hack.
Take a screenshot of
your thumbnail and title
and then drop it
into ChatGPT and ask
what are the top
three questions someone would
want answered if they
click this. It is
incredibly accurate. It's very
good. And it's going
to help you clarify
what your intro needs
to promise. Now, try
not to. Overthink this.
You do need to
fail as fast as
you can many, many
times until you start
to understand your viewers
more and can just
know what these questions
are going to be
every time. And then
move on to step
two. So step two
of the intro is
your opening line, which
is known as the
hook. This is the
first thing your viewers
hear. And it's the
first of our three
building blocks for a
great introduction. And all
a hook has to
do is instantly grab
attention, create curiosity and
signal that there's clear
value. And then you
can start to see
the relevance. You also
need to do this
in under five seconds.
So it's an art
form to matter. Annoyingly,
there are an infinite
amount of ways to
hook people. But there's
five types that I
tend to use. So
let's break them down.
Have you ever wondered
why one of your
videos gets a load
of views and then
the next one doesn't
do as well? Now,
I call that a
question hook. You just
ask the viewers a
question they've always wanted
to know the answer
to. And that gets
easier to work out
as we fail as
fast as we can.
And we learn lessons
over time about them.
Next, we have this
type of hook. I'm
a multimillionaire and I
don't own my house
and I don't invest
in any property. Now,
I love that hook
because it's about being
contrarian and saying something
that goes against the
grain of the normal
advice, just like our
cognitive dissonance thumbnail style
does. So with that
example, viewers want to
know why the millionaire
doesn't do what all
the other millionaires do.
So they stick about.
And then next we
have this type of
hook. The second your
video loads, people judge
you. And if they
don't like what they
see, they're going to
leave and you're never
going to generate views.
And so that is
a strong statement hook.
They're powerful because you
blast out a big,
bold claim that makes
the viewer pay attention.
And then we have
this one. American millennials
spend more than three
and a half hours
on their phone every
day. So that was
a surprising fact hook.
The idea here is
you give a surprising
fact that makes viewers
go, oh, wow, I
didn't know that. Now,
two things to be
very careful of here.
Firstly, it has to
be a surprising fact.
If it's not, it's
boring. And secondly, it
has to be relevant.
So the content you
can't just go, did
you know duck quacks
don't echo. So in
this video, I'm going
to teach you how
to hit a home
run.
That's cheating and won't
work. And then finally,
we have this example.
Bidded business for 13
years. I've sold nine
companies. My last company
sold for forty six
point two million. I
own acquisition dot com,
which right now does
about seventeen million dollars
a month across our
portfolio. So my advice,
especially to new or
small channels, is to
never start a video
talking about yourself because
new viewers, they don't
care about you. But
if you just have
so much flipping credibility
and so much proof
of results, opening with
a massive achievement can
make your viewers go,
wow, I can't believe
this person's about to
give me some free
advice. So which one
do you use? Well,
there's no set answer.
You just try one.
And if you can't
come up with any,
use the hook bank
I've made you in
the video planning document
down the side. And
then the next step
is this. Once you
grab someone's attention with
a hook, you need
to give them a
reason to care about
the information in the
rest of the video.
And then the next
step is this. And
the best way to
do that is with
one of these three
options. So firstly, you
make them feel seen
by describing their problem
or you make them
feel hope by teasing
the result they want.
Or you combine both
options, which when you
do this right, your
viewers are going to
go, OK, this is
relevant to me. I
need to see where
this goes. And if
you skip this step,
you lose that emotional
connection. People won't care
about listening to the
next line that follows.
So let me break
down a script of
mine that does this.
So you can see.
In action. And I'm
going to do it
with the first option,
which basically just describes
a problem, which I
call poking the problem.
And I'll read it
out to you. Do
you hate making thumbnails?
Every YouTuber I know
does. The thing is,
they're the most important
part of your video,
because if you can't
get a click, nobody
watches and will generate
you any sales. And
all of that time
you spent writing, filming,
anything is wasted. So
that one line, starting
with the thing is
that sets up a
problem viewers actually care
about. But how do
we know what problem
to poke? Well, remember
those top three problems
that we discovered in
phase one? My avatars
are not getting consistent
leads and sales, not
having enough time, not
getting results with the
basic advice online. So
all we do is
we make sure that
this problem in the
intro hits on one
of them. So the
viewer hears it and
thinks, OK, this video
speaks to my problems.
I'm in. So now
let me show you
a version that uses
a result and see
if you can work
out what I'm doing
here. So do you
hate making thumbnails? I
used to until I
figured out a simple
thumbnail formula that generated
millions of views and
six million dollars from
YouTube in just a
few years. So that
time I'm not describing
the pain. I'm teasing
the result that my
viewers want is actually
possible. And can you
see how it still
targets the same kind
of problems from my
list? Right. Generating consistent
sales and leads, but
also time. I said
it only took a
couple of years. And
then for the third
option here, we combine
the problem and the
result. And it might
sound like this. So
do you hate making
funnels? Every YouTube I
know does because they
take so flippin long.
The thing is, they're
the most important part
of your video. If
you don't get a
click, nobody watches or
enters your sales funnel.
So all that time
you put in goes
to waste. But there's
a special formula for
thumbnails that's fast and
easy to produce and
it's blowing up channels
right now. Now we
are that middle section.
It pokes the problem
here and then the
final section teases the
result. So in just
a few lines, what
you've done is you've
made your viewers feel
like this video might
solve every issue I'm
facing, meaning they're curious
to want to listen
to the final part
of our introduction we
call the setup. So
the setup tells the
viewers. Here's exactly what
you're going to get
in the video. And
a simple formula you
can use for every
time is this. So
in this video, I'm
going to show you
the things they care
about. But what are
about? Well, here all
you do is you
take the top two
to three viewer questions.
You work to step
one and you fill
in the blanks of
that template. So here's
an example of that
in action. So let's
pretend this was the
thumbnail and title and
the questions we think
the viewers want answers
to are what's the
trick? Why should I
make boring thumbnails? How
will this help? My
business are set up
would sound something like
this. So in this
video, I'm going to
show you what this
simple formula is, why
it's critical you make
boring thumbnails for it
to work and how
to use it to
make your sales explode.
Now, I've color coded
the script there and
the questions viewers might
want an answer to.
So you can kind
of see them getting
ticked off. But what
we've now done is
we've hooked the viewer.
We've positioned the video
as a solution to
the problems they know
they have. And we
want our channel to
be known for. We
then match or hopefully
exceeded their expectations with
what the video might
cover. And then that
moves us on to
step five, the part
everyone seems to get
stuck on, which is
called a transition. So
a transition is basically
the cement that connects
an intro to the
first point or first
lesson of the video
in a way that
makes viewers actually want
to listen to it.
So here's an example
of a script without
one. What I want
to do is I
want you to pay
attention to when you
suddenly have to think
harder about what I'm
saying. All right. So
why do you get
addicted to something? Well,
it's because you love
the feeling. It becomes
a habit and you
miss it when it's
gone. That feeling is
exactly what you want
to create of your
YouTube videos. If you
want to build a
loyal returning audience who
buys from you. So
in this video, I'm
going to show you
the five step process
I've been using inside
of my videos for
years to bring millions
of people back again
and again. Have you
ever really craved something
like chocolate and gone
to your secret stash,
opened the drawer and
there's nothing in there
other than a rice
cake you've been avoiding
for years judging you?
All right. So the
rice cake bit was
the point where you
should have started thinking,
wait a second, what
is going on? Is
this still part of
the process? Is this
still part of the
intro? And then you
would have been thinking,
why the heck is
he talking about rice
cake? Like, I didn't
click on a dessert
video. Just give me
the information I asked
for. So that has
happened because there is
no transition. And without
transition, everything that follows
is going to feel
like waffle to your
viewers because they don't
know why they need
to listen to it.
So to solve that,
all we do is
we slip in a
short sentence that does
two things. Firstly, it
signals one part of
the script has ended
and we're now moving
on to more new
information. Secondly, it hooks
forward to position the
information that follows as
being the solution to
one of the three
problems we know our
buyers care about. So
if I wrote, so
step one is critical.
If you want to
bring viewers back and
turn them into buyers
and it works like
this, we've now told
the viewer the intro
is over, the video
has begun and our
first lesson is going
to show them how
to solve the thing
they care about the
most if they listen
to the rice cake
story. But we never
turn around and say,
let me show you
why you have to
listen. We just set
up the reason why
they listen. And I
would also recommend never
saying these in a
transition. OK, now let's
dove in because that's
something AI says. OK,
let's talk about because
no one came here
to talk to you.
And also, they say,
let me tell you,
because it sounds like
you're going to tell
them a list of
boring information. So instead,
any transitions, I just
say, all right, so
let me show you.
Because the way we
write videos relies heavily
on this word, as
you're going to find
out later. So that
is what I recommend
the transition. It may
seem small, but it's
one of the most
powerful ways to keep
a viewer hooked and
people locked in. And
if you want a
list of transitions, there's
some in the transition
bank in the video
planner. All right. So
now let's move on
to step six. Now,
what you have to
accept to grow a
channel is we need
to get cold viewers
to watch a video,
but these cold new
viewers, they don't like
you. They distrust you.
And that makes it
very, very hard to
get past our intro
or even the video
making. So at some
point in your intro,
what you have to
do is quickly prove
that you know what
you're talking about. So
they go, OK, this
person's legit. I'm going
to keep watching them
because most people on
YouTube, they have no
real credibility and they
are just repurposing blog
posts. So we have
to make it very
clear we're legit and
not one of them.
So to fix this,
we bake something I
call a credibility line
somewhere into your hook,
your problem result section
or your setup in
a way that it
kind of feels like
a natural part of
the support of the
information, not like a
random line of a
CV inserted. And the
way you do that
is to show a
big result you got,
like fixing this made
me ninety thousand dollars.
Or by mentioning your
vast experience, like after
making 500 cakes over
three years, here's what
finally made them moist.
Or you could name
drop clients or results.
We've used this on
over 40 people and
it's worked every time.
Or you could signal
just effort saying I
analysed five hundred resumes.
And this is what
got me. This is
what people employed. So
here's my script with
the line sprinkled in
somewhere. I want you
to think about what
section is in the
hook, the problem result
or the setup. But
I've now colour coded
this one so you
can see it in
action. Red is the
hook. Orange is the
problem result. Green is
the setup. Blue is
the transition. And that
is it. So it
sounds like this. This
video is one of
the fastest and easiest
I've ever made and
one of the best
performing for sales and
the framework I used
to make it didn't
just work once. It
blew up sales multiple
times. I've got hundreds
of emails too. So
now I'm going to
give you every step
to make your own
so you can just
copy it. So what's
this video? Why should
you make it? OK,
so to finish up
our intro section, I
want to bring up
three mistakes that you
want to avoid when
you are writing your
intro. And the first
is you need to
make sure you're not
really vague and general
with your words. If
you do tease a
specific problem or a
result in that section,
say the problem or
the result. Don't say
things like this works
so well. Say this
will knock £15 off
in four days. Now,
the next thing you
need to think about
is not educating. So
the intro is the
place to raise curiosity
and to hook. If
you start giving lessons
before the set up
of value, you're going
to turn what should
be one of the
easiest parts of your
video for a viewer
to grasp into a
massive turnoff that overwhelms
them and confuse them.
So stay away from
giving value. Just hook.
The next is not
showing proof. Now, if
you ever make a
claim anywhere in your
intro, the information you're
going to give them
gets results. Show visual
proof or testimonial before
and after or a
striped bank or graph
or something. If you
can't, you can't. But
if you can, do
not be lazy. Look
at my videos. Every
single one in the
intro. As soon as
I say something, bam,
there's proof of results.
And it's one of
the reasons you're here.
OK, so before we
move on to how
to write your intro,
what I want to
do is I want
you to do the
quiz below to make
sure you kind of
fully understand this content.
And then in the
next video, move on
to writing.